A Guide to the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial records FA061
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Appropriations, 1917-1949; 3
  - Appropriations - Social Studies, 3_06
    - Foreign Language Information Service - Special Fund, 1927-1928 (Box 52, Folder 556)
    - Mildred Fry Foundation, 1928 (Box 52, Folder 557)
    - German Situation Survey - Ford, 1924 (Box 52, Folder 558)
      Relief; social services.
    - Germanic Society of America, 1923-1924 (Box 52, Folder 559)
      Advisory Committee. Journals to German and Austrian libraries. Franz Boas.
    - Glueck, Sheldon, 1926 (Box 52, Folder 560)
    - Hamburg Institute of International Affairs, 1925-1930 (Box 52, Folder 561)
      Research facilities in politics.
    - Hanover Conference - Social Scientists, 1925-1926 (Box 52, Folder 562)
      Precursor to Social Science Research Council Hanover Conferences.
    - Hanover Conference - Social Scientists - Report (Box 52, Folder 563)
    - Hanover Conference - Psychologists, January-June 1925 (Box 52, Folder 564)
    - Hanover Conference - Psychologists, July 1925-1926 (Box 53, Folder 565)
    - Hanover Conference - Psychologists - Report, 1925 (Box 53, Folder 566)
    - Hanover Conference - Psychologists - Report, 1925 (Box 53, Folder 567)
    - Hanover Conference - Psychologists - Report, 1925 (Box 53, Folder 568)
    - Hanover Conference - Joint Committee Report, 1925 (Box 53, Folder 569)
    - Harvard University - Business School Library, 1927-1932 (Box 53, Folder 570)
      LSRM-RF. Cataloging and reclassifying.
    - Harvard University - Filipiana, 1925-1936 (Box 53, Folder 571)
      LSRM-RF. Purchase of Beyer collections of books, manuscripts, and specimens relating to the Philippines.
    - Harvard University - Industrial Relations, 1924-1928 (Box 53, Folder 572)
      Industrial Psychology, extension of Wharton work, Elton Mayo.
    - Hanover Conference - Psychologists - Report, 1925 (Box 53A, Folder 572A)
    - Hanover Conference - Psychologists - Report, 1925 (Box 53A, Folder 572B)
    - Harvard University - International Relations, 1923-1942 (Box 54, Folder 573)
      LSRM-RF. Harvard and Radcliffe research.
    - Harvard University - International Relations, 1923-1942 (Box 54, Folder 574)
    - Harvard University - Pribram, 1927 (Box 54, Folder 575)
      Visiting Professor.
    - Howard University - Law and Social Sciences Library, 1927-1928 (Box 54, Folder 576)
    - Institute for Comparative Research in Human Culture - Kola, 1925-1932 (Box 54, Folder 577)
      LSRM-RF. General background information, Oslo - language and culture of Arctic people. Kola expedition. Franz Boas.
    - Institute for Comparative Research in Human Culture - Kola, 1925-1932 (Box 54, Folder 578)
    - Institute for Comparative Research in Human Culture - Kola, 1925-1932 (Box 54, Folder 579)
    - Institut fur Sozial und Staatswissenschaften an Heidelberg, 1928-1936 (Box 54, Folder 580)
      LSRM-RF. Research in social sciences and political science.
    - Institute of Economics and History, 1926-1931 (Box 54, Folder 581)
      LSRM-RF. Copenhagen, general background information.
    - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1925-1929 (Box 54, Folder 582)
      LSRM-RF. Research and conferences in social sciences in Pacific.
    - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1925-1929 (Box 54, Folder 583)
    - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1925-1929 (Box 54, Folder 584)
    - International Conference of Social Work, 1924-1928 (Box 54, Folder 585)
    - International Congress of Americanists, 1927-1929 (Box 55, Folder 586)
      Pre-Columbian America; non-European life of the American colonial system. Cross-discipline. Franz Boas.
    - International Institute for African Language and Culture, 1925-1929 (Box 55, Folder 587)
    - International Migration Service, 1924-1929 (Box 55, Folder 588)
      Individual social problems which require cooperation in more than one country, general background information.
    - International Migration Service, 1924-1929 (Box 55, Folder 589)
    - International Philosophical Congress, 1925 (Box 55, Folder 590)
      Expenses.
    - Lingelbach, William, 1926-1928 (Box 55, Folder 591)
      Representative, social studies fellowships in Europe.
    - London School of Economics, 1923-1932 (Box 55, Folder 592)
    - London School of Economics - Building Fund, 1923-1932 (Box 55, Folder 593)
      LSRM-RF. Library, Catalog, William Beveridge.
    - London School of Economics - Building Fund, 1923-1932 (Box 55, Folder 594)
    - London School of Economics - Research, 1924-1933 (Box 55, Folder 595)
      LSRM-RF. Aid professors, readers, and lecturers in their research.
    - London School of Economics - Research, 1924-1933 (Box 55, Folder 596)
    - London School of Economics - Reports (Box 55, Folder 597)
    - London School of Economics - Reports (Box 55, Folder 598)
    - Malinowski, B., 1925-1926 (Box 56, Folder 599)
      Visiting professor.
    - Marshall, L. C., 1924-1929 (Box 56, Folder 600)
    - Merriam, Charles, 1925-1928 (Box 56, Folder 601)
      Special services; research assistants.
    - Merriam, Charles, 1925-1928 (Box 56, Folder 602)
    - Mexican Study, 1924-1927 (Box 56, Folder 603)
      Study of Mexican labor migration into United States, through Social Science Research Council.
    - Mitchell, Welsley, 1925-1926 (Box 56, Folder 604)
    - Montana Project, 1923-1924 (Box 56, Folder 605)
      Advisory Committee, "FairWay" Farms Company. Sound landlord-tenant relations. Henry C. Taylor.
      See Northwestern University Institute for Research in Land Economics.
    - Museum and Laboratory of Anthropology at Santa Fe, 1927-1940 (Box 56, Folder 606)
      LSRM-RF. Investigation, training graduate students in laboratory and field technique, education of the general public.
    - National Bureau of Economic Research - Publication Fund, 1926 (Box 56, Folder 607)
      Through Social Science Research Council.
    - National Council for Social Sciences, 1922-1924 (Box 56, Folder 608)
    - National Industrial Conference Board - Pamphlet (Box 56, Folder 609)
    - National Institute of Industrial Psychology, 1923-1929 (Box 56, Folder 610)
      LSRM-Rf. Research in industry and commerce based on principles of psychology and physiology. Practical application, general background information, London.
    - National Institute of Public Administration, 1927-1928 (Box 56, Folder 611)
      Charles Beard to lecture in Yugoslavia; general background information.
    - National Institute of Social Sciences, 1928 (Box 56, Folder 612)
    - National Municipal League, 1926-1932 (Box 56, Folder 613)
      LSRM-RF. Coordinate local bureaus with other civic agencies - national cooperation.
    - National Municipal League, 1926-1932 (Box 56, Folder 614)
    - National Municipal League - Reports (Box 57, Folder 615)
    - National Personnel Administration, 1922 (Box 57, Folder 616)
    - National Research Council, 1922-1929 (Box 57, Folder 617)
      Vernon Kellog. George E. Hale. A. V. Kidder.
    - National Research Council, 1922-1929 (Box 57, Folder 618)
    - National Research Council, 1922-1929 (Box 57, Folder 619)
    - National Research Council - Reports (Box 57, Folder 620)
    - National Research Council - Reports (Box 57, Folder 621)
    - National Research Council - Conference Fund, 1927-1929 (Box 57, Folder 622)
      LSRM-RF. Conference on deaf, experimental psychology, racial differences.
    - National Research Council - Conference Fund - Reports (Box 57, Folder 623)
    - National Research Council - Deaf Projects, 1922-1930 (Box 58, Folder 624)
      LSRM-RF. Survey of schools, physical cause of deafness, Percival Hall, Robert Gault, Raymond Dodge, Charles w. Richardson.
      Photographs removed to RAC Photograph Collection, Series 1016, Box 2, Folder 20.
    - National Research Council - Deaf Projects, 1922-1930 (Box 58, Folder 625)
    - National Research Council - Deaf Projects, 1922-1930 (Box 58, Folder 626)
    - National Research Council - Deaf Projects, 1922-1930 (Box 58, Folder 627)
    - National Research Council - Deaf Projects - Reports (Box 58, Folder 628)
    - National Research Council - Human Migration, 1922-1925 (Box 58, Folder 629)
      LSRM-RF. Measuring and evaluating human traits, mental measurement, analysis of personality, pathology of race. Robert M. Yerkes, Clark Wissler.
    - National Research Council - Human Migration, 1922-1925 (Box 58, Folder 630)
    - National Research Council - Human Migration, 1922-1925 (Box 58, Folder 631)
    - National Research Council - Human Migration, 1926-1930 (Box 59, Folder 632)
    - National Research Council - Human Migration - Pamphlets (Box 59, Folder 633)
    - National Research Council - Human Migration - Reports (Box 59, Folder 634)
    - National Research Council - Human Migration - Reports (Box 59, Folder 635)
    - National Research Council - Population Conference, 1927-1928 (Box 59, Folder 636)
      Geneva.
    - National Research Council - Union of Population, 1927-1929 (Box 59, Folder 637)
      LSRM-RF. International union for further study; result of conference.
    - National Student Forum, 1922 (Box 59, Folder 638)
    - Netherland - American Foundation, 1924 (Box 59, Folder 639)
    - New England Council, 1926 (Box 59, Folder 640)
    - New Jersey State League of Municipalities, 1929 (Box 59, Folder 641)
    - New School for Social Research, 1924-1929 (Box 59, Folder 642)
    - New York School of Social Work, 1923-1928 (Box 59, Folder 643)
      LSRM-RF. Endowment, develop faculty and research program. Porter Lee.
    - New York School of Social Work, 1923-1928 (Box 59, Folder 644)
    - New York School of Social Work, 1929-1931 (Box 60, Folder 645)
    - New York School of Social Work - Reports (Box 60, Folder 646)
    - Newcomb, Robinson, 1926-1927 (Box 60, Folder 647)
    - Northwestern University - Institute for Research in Land Economics, 1922-1935 (Box 60, Folder 648)
      LSRM-RF. Establish institute, study economic problems related to vitalization of rural and urban land. Tenancy and rural land ownership; general background information, Richard T. Ely, Henry Taylor, Walter Dill Scott.
    - Northwestern University - Institute for Research in Land Economics, 1922-1935 (Box 60, Folder 649)
    - Northwestern University - Institute for Research in Land Economics, 1922-1935 (Box 60, Folder 650)
    - Northwestern University - Institute for Research in Land Economics, 1922-1935 (Box 60, Folder 651)
    - Northwestern University - Institute for Research in Land Economics, 1922-1935 (Box 60, Folder 652)
    - Northwestern University - Institute for Research in Land Economics, 1922-1935 (Box 60, Folder 653)
    - Northwestern University - Institute for Research in Land Economics - Reports (Box 61, Folder 654)
    - Northwestern University - Institute for Research in Land Economics - Reports (Box 61, Folder 655)
    - Northwestern University - Institute for Research in Land Economics - Reports (Box 61, Folder 656)
    - Notgemeinschaft, 1923-1932 (Box 61, Folder 657)
      LSRM-RF. German Emergency Society, social science books and periodicals to libraries. For promotion of research. Franz Boas, August Fehling, F. Schmidt-Ott.
    - Notgemeinschaft, 1923-1932 (Box 61, Folder 658)
    - Notgemeinschaft, 1923-1932 (Box 61, Folder 659)
    - Notgemeinschaft, 1923-1932 (Box 61, Folder 660)
    - Odum, Howard, 1925-1929 (Box 62, Folder 661)
    - Prussian State Library, 1924-1929 (Box 62, Folder 662)
      Social Science literature.
    - Radcliffe College, 1924-1929 (Box 62, Folder 663)
    - Royal Anthropological Institute, 1924-1930 (Box 62, Folder 664)
      LSRM-RF.
    - Scarritt College, 1925-1929 (Box 62, Folder 665)
    - School of Applied Social Sciences, 1924-1932 (Box 62, Folder 666)
      LSRM-RF. Public Health Nursing, special education for social work, library service training course - at Western Reserve, general background information.
    - School of Applied Social Sciences, 1924-1932 (Box 62, Folder 667)
    - School of Applied Social Sciences, 1924-1932 (Box 62, Folder 668)
    - School of Applied Social Sciences, 1924-1932 (Box 62, Folder 669)
    - School of Applied Social Sciences, 1924-1932 (Box 62, Folder 670)
    - Schools of Business Administration, 1923-1929 (Box 62, Folder 671)
      L. C. Marshall study.
    - Schools of Social Work, 1924-1925 (Box 62, Folder 672)
      S. H. Walker study.
    - Schools of Social Work, 1926-1929 (Box 63, Folder 673)
    - Sherwell, Guillermo, 1924-1925 (Box 63, Folder 674)
      Study of social welfare in Latin America.
    - Smith College - School for Social Work, 1924-1927 (Box 63, Folder 675)
    - Social Science, 1925-1928 (Box 63, Folder 676)
    - Social Sciences - Policy (Box 63, Folder 677)
      LSRM.
    - Social Science - Pamphlet and Report (Box 63, Folder 678)
    - Social Science - Pamphlet and Report (Box 63, Folder 679)
      Includes "The Status of Social Science in the United States" by Lawrence K. Frank
    - Social Sciences in France - Rist Survey, 1923-1926 (Box 63, Folder 680)
    - Social Sciences - Roumania, 1927-1928 (Box 63, Folder 681)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1923-1931 (Box 64, Folder 682)
      LSRM-RF. Charles E. Merriam, Wesley Mitchell.
    - Social Science Research Council, 1923-1931 (Box 64, Folder 683)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1923-1931 (Box 64, Folder 684)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1923-1931 (Box 64, Folder 685)
    - Social Science Research Council - Clippings (Box 64, Folder 686)
    - 4 blueprints of charts displaying "Social-Industrial Relationships with Special Reference to Textile Industry", GRAPH (Quantity 4) (Drawer C 2, Folder 8)
      separated from: Box 64, folder 686
    - Social Science Research Council - Reports (Box 64, Folder 687)
    - Social Science Research Council - Abstracts, 1925-1935 (Box 64, Folder 688)
      LSRM-RF. Journal of Social Science Abstracts.
    - Social Science Research Council - Committee on Sex and Family Relationships, 1925-1929 (Box 64, Folder 689)
      Cooperation with National Research Council Studies.
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference, 1926 (Box 64, Folder 690)
      Hanover, Arnold Bennett Hall.
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference - Draft Report, 1926 (Box 65, Folder 691)
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference - Draft Report, 1926 (Box 65, Folder 692)
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference - Draft Report, 1926 (Box 65, Folder 693)
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference - Report, 1926 (Box 65, Folder 694)
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference - Report, 1926 (Box 65, Folder 695)
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference - Report, 1926 (Box 66, Folder 696)
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference - Report, 1926 (Box 66, Folder 697)
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 698)
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference - Report, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 699)
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference - Report, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 700)
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference, 1928 (Box 66, Folder 701)
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference - Report, 1928 (Box 67, Folder 702)
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference - Report, 1928 (Box 67, Folder 703)
    - Social Science Research Council - Conference, 1929 (Box 67, Folder 704)
    - Social Science Research Council - Crime, 1926-1928 (Box 67, Folder 705)
      Crime recording; uniform crime statistics. Lawrence B. Dunham. E. H. Sutherland.
    - Social Science Research Council - Fellowships, 1924-1930 (Box 67, Folder 706)
    - Social Science Research Council - Fellowships, 1924-1930 (Box 67, Folder 707)
    - Social Science Research Council - Fellowships, 1924-1930 (Box 67, Folder 708)
    - Social Science Research Council - Fellowships - Reports (Box 67, Folder 709)
    - Social Science Research Council - Human Migrations, 1924-1930 (Box 68, Folder 710)
      LSRM-RF, with National Bureau of Economic Research.
    - Social Science Research Council - Human Migrations, 1924-1930 (Box 68, Folder 711)
    - Social Science Research Council - Human Migrations, 1924-1930 (Box 68, Folder 712)
    - Social Science Research Council - International News, 1924-1928 (Box 68, Folder 713)
      Conference about collection and distribution of international news.
    - Social Science Research Council - McComb, 1929 (Box 68, Folder 714)
    - Social Science Research Council - Project Budgets, 1926-1933 (Box 68, Folder 715)
    - Social Science Research Council - Project Budgets, 1926-1933 (Box 68, Folder 716)
    - Social Science Research Council - Project Budgets, 1926-1933 (Box 68, Folder 717)
    - Social Science Research Council - Prohibition Survey, 1925-1927 (Box 68, Folder 718)
    - Social Science Research Council - Rural Sociology, 1928-1933 (Box 68, Folder 719)
      LSRM-RF. Graduate fellowships in agricultural economics and rural sociology.
    - Southern Teachers Conference, 1925-1927 (Box 68, Folder 720)
      At Tulane, University of Virginia and the University of North Carolina. Howard Odum, Wilson Gee.
    - Southworth, Constant, 1925 (Box 69, Folder 721)
    - Stanford University - Food Research Institute, 1922-1929 (Box 69, Folder 722)
      Survey of world trade in principal food commodities.
    - Stanford University - Russian Studies, 1925-1928 (Box 69, Folder 723)
      Economic and social conditions of contemporary Russia.
    - Stanford University - Social Science, 1926-1931 (Box 69, Folder 724)
      LSRM-RF. Development of a program.
    - Stanford University - Pamphlets (Box 69, Folder 725)
    - Study of Abnormals, 1925-1926 (Box 69, Folder 726)
      Liquor problem.
    - State Agricultural College - Colorado, 1929 (Box 69, Folder 727)
    - Swarthmore College, 1925 (Box 69, Folder 728)
    - Syracuse University - School of Citizenship, 1926-1928 (Box 69, Folder 729)
      Summer School, research assistance and facilities; general background information.
    - Syracuse University - School of Citizenship - Reports (Box 69, Folder 730)
    - Taussig, F. W., 1923-1927 (Box 69, Folder 731)
    - Taylor, Maurice, 1926-1928 (Box 69, Folder 732)
    - Thomas, Dorothy, 1926-1927 (Box 69, Folder 733)
    - Thomas, W. I., 1925-1929 (Box 69, Folder 734)
      Survey for study on juvenile delinquency.
    - Thomas, W. I., 1925-1929 (Box 69, Folder 735)
    - Thomas, W. I. - Report (Box 69, Folder 736)
    - Thompson, J. W., 1924 (Box 70, Folder 737)
    - Thurstone, F. L. - Pamphlet (Box 70, Folder 738)
    - Tulane University, 1923-1932 (Box 70, Folder 739)
      LSRM-RF. Training course for social workers; graduate program; strengthen social sciences; behavior clinic.
    - Tulane University, 1923-1932 (Box 70, Folder 740)
    - Tulane University - Pamphlets (Box 70, Folder 741)
    - United States Department of Agriculture, 1924-1925 (Box 70, Folder 742)
    - University of Birmingham, 1927 (Box 70, Folder 743)
    - University of Chicago, 1923-1931 (Box 70, Folder 744)
      LSRM-RF. L. C. Marshall, Max Mason, David H. Stevens, William E. Dodd.
    - University of Chicago - Reports (Box 70, Folder 745)
    - University of Chicago - Anthropology, 1925-1926 (Box 70, Folder 746)
      Psychological and linguistic. James H. Tufts, Fay-Cooper Cole.
    - University of Chicago - Civic Education, 1924-1933 (Box 70, Folder 747)
      LSRM-RF. Methods of civic education in various countries.
    - University of Chicago - Civic Education, 1924-1933 (Box 70, Folder 748)
    - University of Chicago - Community Research, 1923-1928 (Box 70, Folder 749)
      LSRM-RF. Contribution of social sciences to scientific method and achievements; practical service in research facilities and assistance. L. C. Marshall, Leonard D. White.
    - University of Chicago - Community Research, 1923-1928 (Box 70, Folder 750)
    - University of Chicago - Community Research, 1929-1932 (Box 71, Folder 751)
    - University of Chicago - Community Research - Reports (Box 71, Folder 752)
    - University of Chicago - Community Research - Reports (Box 71, Folder 753)
    - University of Chicago - Community Research - Reports (Box 71, Folder 754)
    - University of Chicago - Community Research - Reports (Box 71, Folder 755)
    - University of Chicago - Research in Chicago, 1923-1924 (Box 71, Folder 756)
    - University of Chicago - School of Commerce and Administration, 1924 (Box 71, Folder 757)
    - University of Chicago - Secondary Schools, 1923-1928 (Box 71, Folder 758)
      Commercial Studies.
    - University of Chicago - Social Science, 1927-1933 (Box 72, Folder 759)
    - University of Chicago - Social Science - Pamphlets (Box 72, Folder 760)
    - University of Chicago - Social Service Administration, 1924-1931 (Box 72, Folder 761)
      School of Social Work; endowment, general background information.
    - University of Chicago - Social Service Administration, 1924-1931 (Box 72, Folder 762)
    - University of Chicago - Social Service Administration, 1924-1931 (Box 72, Folder 763)
    - University of Chicago - Social Service Administration, 1924-1931 (Box 72, Folder 764)
    - University of Chicago - Social Service Administration, 1924-1931 (Box 72, Folder 765)
    - University of Chicago - Social Service Administration - Pamphlets and Reports (Box 73, Folder 766)
    - University of Cologne, 1925 (Box 73, Folder 767)
    - University of Denver, 1925-1931 (Box 73, Folder 768)
      LSRM-RF. Establish a Bureau of Statistical Research in economics; intermountain survey, general background information.
    - University of Denver, 1925-1931 (Box 73, Folder 769)
    - University of Denver - Pamphlets (Box 73, Folder 770)
    - University of Kiel, 1923 (Box 73, Folder 771)
    - University of Liverpool - Liverpool Survey, 1927-1931 (Box 73, Folder 772)
      LSRM-RF. Causes of poverty.
    - University of Liverpool - Liverpool Survey, 1927-1931 (Box 73, Folder 773)
    - University of Manchester, 1923 (Box 73, Folder 774)
    - University of Missouri, 1926-1928 (Box 73, Folder 775)
    - University of North Carolina, 1924-1928 (Box 74, Folder 776)
      Howard Odum.
    - University of North Carolina, 1924-1928 (Box 74, Folder 777)
    - University of North Carolina, 1924-1928 (Box 74, Folder 778)
    - University of North Carolina - Reports (Box 74, Folder 779)
    - University of North Carolina Doctor's Degree, 1926 (Box 74, Folder 780)
    - University of North Carolina - Research, 1924-1932 (Box 74, Folder 781)
      LSRM-RF. Institute for Research in all social science departments, Howard Odum, T. J. Woofter.
    - University of North Carolina - Research, 1924-1932 (Box 74, Folder 782)
    - University of North Carolina - Research, 1924-1932 (Box 74, Folder 783)
    - University of North Carolina - Research Library, 1926 (Box 74, Folder 784)
    - University of North Carolina - School of Public Welfare, 1927-1928 (Box 74, Folder 785)
    - University of North Carolina - State Board of Charities, 1924-1928 (Box 75, Folder 786)
      With State Department of Public Welfare, county demonstrations, Howard Odum. Kate Burr Johnson.
    - University of North Carolina - State Board of Charities, 1924-1928 (Box 75, Folder 787)
    - University of North Carolina - Clippings (Box 75, Folder 788)
    - University of Oklahoma, 1926-1928 (Box 75, Folder 789)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1923-1929 (Box 75, Folder 790)
      Advisory Committee. Department of Industrial Research. Industrial psychiatry. Elton Mayo. Joseph H. Willits.
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1923-1929 (Box 75, Folder 791)
    - University of Pennsylvania - Wharton School, 1926-1933 (Box 75, Folder 792)
      LSRM-RF. Extension of work of Department of Industrial Research.
    - University of Pennsylvania - Wharton School, 1926-1933 (Box 75, Folder 793)